Painting Lantern Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
- Painting Italy (Box 209)
  - Known Artists (Box 212)
    - TITIAN de Vecelli Lorenz, 1477-1489 to 1576 (Box 304–307)
      - Drawings (Box 305)
      - Paintings (Box 305)
        - Berlin (Box 305)
        - Boston (Box 305)
        - Brescia (Box 305)
        - Dresden (Box 305)
        - Edinburgh (Box 305)
        - Escorial (Box 305)
        - Florence (Box 305)
          - Palazzo Pitti (Box 305)
          - Uffizi (Box 305)
        - London (Box 305)
          - Bridgewater Collection (Box 305)
          - National Gallery (Box 305)
            - Bacchus and Ariadne (Box 305)
            - Virgin and Child (Box 305)
        - Madrid (Box 305)
          - Prado (Box 305)
          - Bacchanal (Box 305)
          - Charles V (Box 306)
          - Danae (Box 306)
          - Entombment (Box 306)
          - Fall of Man (Box 306)
          - Isabella of Portugal (Box 306)
          - Madonna and Child with SS. Anthony of Padua and Roch (Box 306)
          - Venus and Organist (Box 306)
        - Milan (Box 306)
        - Munich (Box 306)
        - Naples (Box 306)
        - New Haven (Box 306)
        - New York (Box 306)
          - Bache Collection (Box 306)
          - Frick Collection (Box 306)
          - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 306)
        - Padua (Box 306)
        - Paris (Box 306)
          - Louvre (Box 306)
        - Rome (Box 306)
          - Borghese Gallery (Box 306)
            - Sacred and Profane Love (Box 306)
          - Vatican (Box 307)
        - Venice (Box 307)
          - Accademia (Box 307)
            - Pieta (Box 307)
            - Presentation of the Virgin in the Temple (Box 307)
          - Ca d' Oro (Box 307)
          - Fondaco dei Tedeschi (Box 307)
          - Gesuiti (Box 307)
          - Libraria Marciana (Box 307)
          - S. Maria dei Frari (Box 307)
          - S. Maria della Salute (Box 307)
        - Vienna (Box 307)
        - Washington (Box 307)
    - TITO, Ettore, 1859- (Box 307)
    - TORBIDO, Francesco, 1486-1546 (Box 307)
    - TOSI, Arturo (Box 307)
    - TOSINI, Michele, 1503-1577 (Box 307)
    - TREVISANI, Francesco, 1656-1746 (Box 307)
    - TREVISO, Girolamo da (Box 307)
    - TURA, Cosimo, 1430-1495 (Box 307)
      - Bergamo (Box 307)
      - Berlin (Box 308)
      - Cambridge (Box 308)
      - Dresden (Box 308)
      - Ferrara (Box 308)
      - London (Box 308)
      - New York (Box 308)
      - Paris (Box 308)
      - Venice (Box 308)
      - Washington (Box 308)
    - UCELLO, Paolo di Dono, 1396-1397 to 1475 (Box 308)
      - Drawings (Box 308)
      - Paintings (Box 308)
        - Florence (Box 308)
          - Cathedral (Box 308)
          - S. Maria Novella (Box 308)
          - S. Miniato al Monte (Box 308)
          - Uffizi (Box 309)
        - London (Box 309)
          - National Gallery (Box 309)
        - Oxford (Box 309)
        - Paris (Box 309)
          - Louvre (Box 309)
        - Urbino (Box 309)
    - UGOLINO da Siena, d. 1339-1349 (Box 309)
    - UTILI da Faenza (Bertucci, Giovanni Battista), fl. 1505-1515 (Box 309)
    - VACCARO, Andrea, 1598-1670 (Box 309)
    - VAGA, Pierino del (Box 309)
      - Cleveland (Box 309)
      - Genoa (Box 310)
      - Rome (Box 310)
    - VAGNETTI, Giovanni (Gianni), 1898- (Box 310)
    - VALERIANO, Giuseppe (Box 310)
    - VANNI, Andrea, 1332-1414 (Box 310)
      - Cambridge (Box 310)
      - Siena (Box 310)
    - VANNI, Francesco, 1536-1610 (Box 310)
    - VANNINI, Ottavio, 1585-1643 (Box 310)
    - VANVITELLI, Gaspar (SEE: Wittel, Gaspar van in PAINTING HOLLAND) (Box 310)
    - VAROTARI, Alessandro, ("Il Pado Vanino"), 1588-1648 (Box 310)
    - VASARI, Giorgio, 1511-1574 (Box 310)
    - VECCHIETTA, Lorenzo di Pietro, 1412?-1480 (Box 311)
      - Munich (Box 311)
      - Pienza (Box 311)
      - Siena (Box 311)
    - VECELLIO, Francesco, 1483-1559 (Box 311)
    - VEDOVA, Emilio, 1919- (Box 311)
    - VENETO, Bartolommeo, 1490-1555 (Box 311)
    - VENEZIANO (Box 311)
    - VENUSTI, Marcello, 1515-1579 (Box 311)
    - VERONESE, Paolo, 1528-1588 (Box 312)
      - Bergamo (Box 312)
      - Cleveland (Box 312)
      - Dresden (Box 312)
      - London (Box 312)
      - Madrid (Box 312)
      - Maser (Box 312)
      - Modena (Box 312)
      - New York (Box 312)
      - Paris (Box 312)
      - Rome (Box 312)
      - Venice (Box 312)
        - Accademia (Box 312)
        - Ducal Palace (Box 313)
        - S. Sebastiano (Box 313)
      - Verona (Box 313)
      - Vienna (Box 313)
      - Washington (Box 313)
    - VERROCCHIO, Andrea del, 1436-1488 (Box 313)
      - Photographs (Box 313)
      - Drawings (Box 313)
      - Paintings (Box 313)
        - Florence (Box 313)
        - London (Box 313)
        - New York (Box 313)
    - VERROCCHIO, school of (Box 313)
    - VITI, Timoteo della (Timoteo da Urbino), 1469-1523 (Box 313)
    - VIVARINI, Alviso, 1445-1446 to 1503-1505 (Box 314)
    - VIVARINI, Antonio (da Murano), 1415 to 1476-1484 (Box 314)
    - VIVARINI, Bartolommeo (da Murano), 1432-1499 (Box 314)
    - VOLTERRA, Daniele da (SEE: Daniele da Volterra) (Box 314)
    - ZAGNELLI, Bernardino di Bosio, 1460-1470 to 1510-1512 (Box 314)
    - ZENALE, Bernardinio, 1436-1526 (Box 314)
    - ZOPPO, Marco, 1433-1478 (Box 314)
    - ZOTTO, Giovanni Francesco dal, 1450-1510 (Box 314)
      X Giovanni Francesco da Tolmezzo
    - ZUCCARELLI, Francesco, 1702-1788 (Box 314)
    - ZUCCARI, Federico (Box 314)
    - ZUCCARI, Taddeo, 1529-1566 (Box 314)
    - ZUCCI, Jacopo, 1541-1590 (Box 314)
- Painting Italy -- Materials transferred to the Yale University Art Gallery
  - 12th century
    - CROSS #432
  - 13th century
    - CRUCIFIXES
    - MADONNAS and Child
    - S. Michael Altarpiece
    - ASSISI
    - ROME
    - S. Gimignano
    - SUBIACO
    - ISAAC Master, 13th century
    - MASTER of the Bigallo, 13th century
    - MASTER of the Franciscan Crucifix
    - MAGDALEN Master
    - MASTER of S. Martino
  - 14th century
    - MASTER of Citta di Castello, late 14th century
    - MASTER of Palazzo Venezia
    - MASTER of S. Cecelia, early 14th century
    - MASTER of S. Martino alla Palma
    - MASTER of the Blessed Clare
    - MASTER of the Fabriano Altarpiece
    - MASTER of the Oville Madonna
    - MASTER of the Rinuccini Chapel
    - MASTER of the Life of S. John
    - MASTER of the S. George Codex
    - MASTER of the S. Verdiana Panel
    - ROMAGNOLE Master
    - FAKES
  - Known Artists
    - ALTICHIERO da Zevio, 1320-1365
    - ANDREA di Bartolo, 1371-1428
    - BERLINGHIERI, Berlinghiero
    - BERLINGHIERI, Bonaventura
    - BICCI di Lorenzo, 1373-1450
    - CAVALLINI, Pietro, ca.1250-ca.1330
    - CECCO di Pietro, 1333-1366
    - CIMABUE, Giovanni, ca. 1240-1302
      - Assisi
        - S. Francesco
          - Lower Church
          - Upper Church
      - Florence
        - S. Croce
        - Uffizi
      - Paris
      - Washington
    - DADDI, Bernardo, fl. ca. 1280-1348
      - Florence
      - Washington
    - DADDI, Bernardo (school of)
    - DUCCIO di Buononsegna, ca.1255-before 1319
      - Florence
        - S. Maria Novella
      - London
      - New York
      - Siena
        - Opera del Duomo Maesta
          - Life of Virgin
          - Scenes from Life of Christ
            - Christ Entering Jerusalem
            - Washing Feet
            - Kiss of Judas
            - Flagellation
            - Peter Denying Christ
            - Mocking of Christ
            - Crucifixion
            - Noli Me Tangere
            - Three Marys at Tomb
            - Way to Emmaus
            - Doubting Thomas
        - Pinacoteca
      - Washington
    - DUCCIO (followers of)
    - ENRICO di Tedice, ca. 1200-1300
    - FRANCHI, Rosello di Jacopo, 1376-1456
    - GADDI, Agnolo, 1333-1396
      - Florence
      - New Haven
      - Washington
    - GADDI, Taddeo, fl. ca. 1325, d. 1366
      - New Haven
      - Paris
    - GENTILE da Fabriano, ca. 1370-1427
      - Florence
        - Uffizi
          - Adoration of the Magi
      - Milan
      - New Haven
      - New York
      - Washington
    - GERINI, Lorenzo di Niccolo, 1368-1440
    - GERINI, Niccolo di Pietro, fl. 1368-1415
    - GIOTTINO
    - GIOTTO di Bondone, ca. 1266-1337
      - Assisi
        - S. Francesco
          - Lower Church
          - Crossing
            - Allegory of Poverty
            - Allegory of Obedience
            - Glorification of S. Francis
          - Transept
          - Upper Church
            - Life of S. Francis
              - I. Simple Man
              - II. Gives Cloak
              - III. Dream of Palace
              - IV.-------Missing Card
              - V. Renounces Wealth
              - VI. Vision of Pope Innocent III
              - VII. Innocent Approving Rules
              - VIII. Transported to Church/Cart of Fire
              - IX. Praying Vision of Thrones
              - X. Drives Out Demons
              - XI. Before Sultan
              - XII. In Ecstasy
              - XIII. Institutes Nativity
              - XIV. Miracle of Spring
              - XV. Preaching to Birds
              - XVI. Death of Celano
              - XVII. Preaching Before Honorius
              - XVIII. At the Council of Arles
              - XIX. Receiving Stigmata
              - XX. Death of S. Francis
              - XXI. Dream of Guido and Agostino
              - XXII. Girolamo d' Assisi
              - XXIII. At S. Damiano
              - XXIV. Canonization of S. Francis
              - XXV. Vision of Gregory
              - XXVI.-------Missing Card
              - XXVII. Reviving Woman
              - XXVIII. Freeing from Prison
      - Berlin
      - Boston
      - Chantilly
      - Florence
        - Museo Nazionale Bargello
        - S. Croce
          - Bardi Chapel
            - Renouncing Wealth
            - Appearing to Guido and Agostino
            - Apparition at Arles
            - Approving the Rule
            - Death of S. Francis
            - Trial by Fire
          - Peruzzi Chapel
            - Feast of Herod
            - Birth of the Baptist
            - The Evangelist on Patmos
            - Annunciation to Zaccharias
            - Raising of Drusiana
            - Ascension of Evangelist
        - Uffizi
      - Padua
        - Arena Chapel
          - Life of the Virgin
            - Joachim Driven from the Temple
            - Joachim with the Shepherds
            - Annunciation to S. Anne
            - Joachim's Sacrifice
            - Joachim's Dream
            - Meeting at the Golden Gate
            - Birth of the Virgin
            - Presentation of the Virgin in the Temple
            - Distribution of the Rods
            - Watching of the Rods
            - Marriage of the Virgin
            - Virgin's Return Home
            - Annunciation
            - Visitation
          - Life of Christ
            - Nativity
            - Adoration of the Magi
            - Presentation in the Temple
            - Flight into Egypt
            - Massacre of the Innocents
            - Christ and the Doctors
            - Baptism of Christ
            - Wedding at Cana
            - Raising of Lazarus
            - Entry into Jerusalem
            - Merchants Driven from Temple
            - Betrayal of Judas
            - Last Supper
            - Christ Washing the Feet of the Apostles
            - Kiss of Judas
            - Christ before Caiphas
            - Christ Mocked
            - Road to Calvary
            - Crucifixion
            - Lamentatino
            - Noli Me Tangere
            - Ascension
            - Pentecost
            - Christ in the Garden and Flagellation
            - Last Judgment
            - Allegorical Figures
      - Rome
      - Washington
    - GIOVANNI da Bologna, fl. 1377-1390
    - GIOVANNI da Milano, fl. 1346-1369
    - GIOVANNI da Udine, 1487-1564
    - GIOVANNI del Grassi
    - GIOVANNI del Biondo, fl. 1356, d. 1399
    - GIOVANNI di Bartolommeo Cristiano
    - GIOVANNI di Francesco
    - GIOVANNI di Nicola da Pisa, fl. 1358-1360
    - GIUNTA, Pisano, fl. 1180-1202 to 1236-1258
    - GUARIENTO, Padovano, fl. 1338-1367 or 1376
    - JACOPO di Cione
    - JACOPO di Paolo, fl. 1390-1426
    - LIPPO, Vanni, fl. 1341-1375
    - LORENZETTI, Ambrogio, d. ca. 1348
      - Boston
      - Cambridge
      - Florence
      - Massa Marittima
      - Rapolano
      - Siena
        - Palazzo Pubblico
          - Bad Government
          - Good Government
        - Pinacoteca
        - S. Francesco
    - LORENZETTI, Pietro, fl. 1306-d. ca. 1348
      - Assisi
      - Berlin
      - Florence
      - Siena
        - Pinacoteca
    - LORENZETTI, school of
      - Cambridge
      - Pisa
      - Siena
      - Viterbo
    - LORENZO di Bicci, ca. 1350-ca. 1423
    - LORENZO Monaco, 1370-1425
      - Berlin
      - Florence
        - Accademia
        - Uffizi
      - London
      - New York
      - Paris
      - Posen
      - Rome
    - LORENZO, Venenziano, fl. 1356-1379
    - LUCA di Tomme, 1330-1389
      - New Haven
    - MARIOTTO di Nardo, fl. 1394-1424
    - MARTINO di Bartolommeo di Biagio, fl. 1387-1434
    - MASOLINO (Tommaso di Christorore Fini), 1383?-1447?
      - Bremen
      - Castiglioneolona
      - Empoli
      - Florence
        - S. Maria del Carmine
          - Temptation of Adam and Eve
          - Healing the Cripple and Raising Tabitha
      - London
      - Munich
      - Naples
      - Philadelphia
      - Rome
      - Washington
    - MEMMI, Lippo (Filippo di Memmi), d. 1356-1357
      - Berlin
      - Florence
      - New Haven
      - Orvieto
      - Pisa
      - San Gimignano
      - Siena
    - MENABUOI, Giusto de, fl. 1363-1393
    - NARDO di Cione, fl. 1360
    - NELLI, Ottaviano di Martino, 1370-1375 to 1445-1450
    - NICCOLO di Segna, fl. 1330-1340
    - NICCOLO di Ser Sozzo Tegliacci, fl. 1334-1363
    - NICCOLO di Tommaso, fl. 1343-1376
    - PAOLO di Giovanni Fei, 1372-1410
    - PAOLO Veneziano, 1333-1362
    - PAOLO and Giovanni Veneziano
    - PELLICCIAIO, Giacomo di Mino del, fl. 1362-1398
    - PONTE, Giovanni del (Giovanni di Marco), 1385-1437
    - PUCCINELLI, Angelo, fl. 1350-1399
    - SEGNA di Bonaventura, fl. 1298-1330
    - SIMONE del Crocifissi, ca. 1330-1399
    - SIMONE Martini
      - Assisi
      - Berlin
      - Cambridge
      - Florence
      - Naples
      - Paris
      - Pisa
      - Siena
    - STEFANO di Giovanni da Verona ("da Zavio"), 1374-1375 to 1438
    - TADDEO di Bartolo, ca. 1363-1422
      - Cambridge
      - Montepulciano
      - Paris
      - Perugia
      - Pisa
      - Rome
      - San Gimignano
      - Siena
      - Volterra
    - TRAINI, Francesco, fl. 1341-1347
      - Pisa
        - Campo Santo
          - Inferno
          - Last Judgment
          - Triumph of Death
          - Scenes from Anchorites